The serial graviton incidents have been increasing in both scale and prevalence...
一週間前
初めての犠牲者が出たのを皮切りに
...since the first victim last week.
<Graviton>
連続虚空爆破事件は
その威力及び範囲を拡大させています
The times and places of their occurrences are apparently unrelated.
場所も時間も関連性が認められず
We are examining evidence from the scenes using psychometry,
遺留品をサイコメトリーで調べましたが
but we've yet to achieve any results.
依然手がかりは掴めていません
We will cooperate with the Antiskills in order to heighten security further and avoid further victims.
次の犠牲者を出さないためにも
<Antiskill>　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　　
警備員と協力して　一層の警戒強化と
事件解決に全力を
All of our resources will put into solving this case.
放て！心に刻んだ夢を
未来さえ置き去りにして
限界など知らない　意味無い！
この能力が光散らす　その先に遥かな想いを
チカラ
歩いてきた　この道を　振り返ることしか
出来ないなら…今ここで全てを壊せる
暗闇に堕ちる街並み
人はどこまで立ち向かえるの？
加速するその痛みから
誰かをきっと守れるよ
Looking! The blitz loop this planet to search way.
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it. 今すぐ
身体中を　光の速さで　駆け巡った　確かな予感
掴め！望むものなら残さず　輝ける自分らしさで
信じてるよ　あの日の誓いを
この瞳に光る涙　それさえも強さになるから
Are you all right?
大丈夫？
You must have been up late working on the graviton case.
<Graviton>
昨夜も遅くまで調べてたんでしょ　虚空爆破事件
Well, it's my job, after all.
仕方ありませんの
The investigation isn't really going anywhere,
捜査が進展しない以上
so I have to make sure that we're not overlooking something.
見落としがないか確信しなくてはいけませんし
Well, work ethic is all well and good, but don't overdo it, okay?
仕事熱心なのはいいけどさ
あんまり無理しないようにね
Oh, Onee-sama!
へ？ま　お姉様
Are you that worried about me?
そんなに黒子が心配なんですのね
If that's the case, why not sleep with me tonight?
でしたら今夜は一緒にベッドで添い寝していただければ
Kuroko's fatigue would just...!
黒子　疲れなんかすぐに
Huh?
あれ？
Oh, Onee-sama! Please wait!
あぁ　お姉様
待ってくださいですの
Geez, Onee-sama. You're so shy.
もう　お姉様ったら　テレ屋さん
AIM Diffusion Fields are familiar phenomena for Ability Users.
AIM拡散力場は
能力者にとっては身近な現象だ
AIM stands for An Involuntary Movement.
AIMとはAn Involuntary Movementの略
As such, the term refers to the weak powers exuded unconsciously from Ability Users.
能力者が無自覚に周囲に発散している微弱な力というわけだ
Human sensory organs cannot detect AIM Diffusion Fields; we are only able to observe their presence with special equipment.
人間の五感では感じ取れず
専用の機器を使わなければ計測できない
That said, research in the field has been making considerable progress lately.
しかし　目下この分野の研究は成長著しく
Hey!
For example, the Field Resonance effect common among Ability Users of similar types.
例えば
What's wrong?
どうしました？
Why don't we go shopping at Seventh Mist on our way home?
帰り「セブンスミスト」に買い物に行かない
There have even been reports of Ability Users able to consciously manifest and control the fields.
But my job with Judgment...
<Judgement>
でも　風紀委員のお仕事が
It'll be fine if it's just for a little while.
ちょっとぐらい　大丈夫だって
Research is also being conducted with regards to making the fields visible, though this is not a practical goal at the present.
Just say you're out patrolling.
パトロール中とか行っとけばさ
I can't do that this time.
今回はそういうわけにはいかないんですよ
Cases are cases after all.
事件が事件ですし
This would mean that any Ability User's location and ability could be identified individually.
I see...
そうか
Yo.
よう
Can you lend me some scratch?
またちょっと金貸してくんね？
Oh...
え　でも　この間貸した分も返してくれてないよね
You didn't pay me back for last time yet, though...
Huh?
は？
Hey, I told ya I'd pay you back, didn't I?
ちゃんと返すって言ってんだろ
As soon as I get a job.
出世払いでさ
No deadline, no interest, and no limit... those're your selling points, am I right?
だいたいさ　無期限無利息無制限ってのがお前のウリだろ
Come on, you've gotta have more than this.
何だ　これっぽっちかよ
Let's book it before Judgment hits the scene.
<Judgement>
さて　風紀委員が来る前に行こうぜ
Eh, don't worry about them.
楽勝　楽勝
Not like they're gonna show up until after the graviton shit goes down, right?
だってアイツら来んのいつも事件が起こってからだろ
Assholes...!
クソがっ　何やってんだよっ
What're they doing!?
The hell's up with Judgment!?
<Judgement>
何が風紀委員だ
You guys are all useless! I have to do everything by myself!
お前らが無能だからこんな目に遭うんだ
Just wait and see...!
見てろ
Ah, geez!
あぁ　もう
If only we had some more clues...
せめてもう少し手がかりがあれば
Yeah.
そうですよね
About the only thing we know about the perps is that they're at least Level Fours.
<Level 4>
分かってることと言えば　大能力者以上の能力者ということぐらいですし
Unfortunately, there's no at Level Four or higher in the bank.
<Bank>
でも　書庫に該当者はなしですものね
Maybe it's an Ability User who raised his Level over a short period of time!?
もしかして　短期間で急激に力を付けた能力者とか
No way.
まさか　幾ら何でも短期間では無理ですよ
You can't just raise your Level like that.
Right...
ですわよね そんなこと有り得ませんもの
That can't happen.
あ　根気よく　一から遺留品に当たってみましょう
Why don't we go through everything from the beginning one more time?
You're right!
そうですわね
Huh?
Saten-san!
佐天さん
Oh.
Uiharu-san must be busy too.
黒子と一緒で　初春さんも大変でしょ
So it seems.
みたいですね
I asked her to go shopping today, but she turned me down.
今日も買い物誘ったんですけど
断わられちゃって
Well, nothing for it until they catch that bomber guy, I guess.
まぁ　爆弾魔が捕まれまでは仕方ないか
It's just kinda, you know...
なんか　ちょっと　なんだかなって感じなんですよね
Yeah, I get what you mean...
Huh?
へ？
Well, how should I put it...?
いいえ　何って言うか
Uiharu and Shirai-san are both working really hard at Judgment.
<Judgement>
初春や白井さんは風紀委員頑張ってて
And Misaka-san is just amazing.
御坂さんは凄い人だし
But me? I'm just...
あたしはなんーみたいな
Sorry!
っあ　えっと　すいません　そんな重い意味じゃないんです
I wasn't serious!
I just figured that maybe I could do something too if I had an Ability!
ただ　あたしも能力があったら　毎日が変わるかもって
Man... I could become Level Five if I just had a Level Upper.
<Level Upper>　　　　　　　<Level 5>
あぁ　幻想御手とかあれば　超能力者も夢じゃないのにな
Level Upper?
<Level Upper>
幻想御手?
Oh, you know, the urban legend I mentioned earlier.
前に話した都市伝説ですよ
It's supposed to be an item that increases your Level.
<Level>
能力の強さを簡単に引き上げてくれる道具なんですって
I see.
へ？
It turned out that the Undressing Woman really did exist, so I was thinking that maybe...
「脱ぎ女」もいるぐらいだから　ひょっとしてなんって思ってみたんですけど
...Nah. There's no way it exists.
まぁ　あるわけないですよね
Hey.
ね　みんなで行こうか
Huh?
Why don't we all go together?
Shopping with Onee-sama!?
お姉様とお買い物ですか？
You guys are both off, right?
二人共非番でしょ
I figured you needed some R&R.
息抜きにどうかなって佐天さんと話してて
I was talking with Saten-san earlier...
Oh, I see...
そ　そうでしたの
I'm sorry, I have to refuse.
でも　せっかくですが　やめておきますわ
I want to investigate a bit more.
もう少し調べてみたいんですの
I see.
そう　分かった　頑張ってね
All right.
Good luck.
Good night.
おやすみ
This is the dawn of a new world...
新しい世界が来る
A world where I look after myself...
僕が僕を救う
Oh, Shirai-san couldn't come?
そう言えば　白井さん来られなかったんですね
Let's get her something for her.
なんかお土産買いましょうか
うん　いいね
Good idea.
I don't need Judgment if they can't even look after me.
<Judgement>
僕を救わなかった風紀委員は
いらない
A Certain Scientific Railgun
#7
Ability
and
Power
能
力
与
量
This way! This way!
こっち　こっち
Anywhere you want to go, Uiharu-san?
初春さんは見たいとこある？
Not really.
うん　特に決めてないんですけど
Uiharu!
う～い～は～る　ちょっと　ちょっと
Come on!
What is it?
なん　なんですか？
Here!
じゃん！　こんなのはどうじゃ？
How about this?
Impossible! Impossible!
無理無理無理です
I could never wear those!
そんなの穿けるわけないじゃないですか
You can show them off to people when I lift your skirt!
これならあたしにスカートめくられても
堂々と周りに見せつけられるんじゃない
Please don't do that!
見せないでください
Please don't lift up my skirt!
めくらないでください
Ah, too bad.
ありゃ　残念
Misaka-san, looking for something?
あ　御坂さん　何か探しものあります？
え？　そうね
Yeah, I'm looking for some pajamas.
私はパジャマとか
They're over here!
だったら　こっちですよ
I've been looking around,
色々回ってるんだけど　あんまりいいの置いてないのよね
but they don't really have anything good.
Oh.
Hey, hey!
ねね　これすごく可愛い
This looks really cute!
わ　見てよ　初春　このパジャマ
Look at these, Uiharu!
こんな子供っぽいのいまどき着る人いないよね
Come on, someone our age wouldn't be caught dead wearing these.
I mean, I wore stuff like this up until elementary school, but...
小学生の時くらいまではこういうの着てましたけど
wearing them now would be pretty...
さすがに今は
You're right!
そ　そうよね　中学生にもなって　これはないわよね
They're no good for middle schoolers, right!?
Yeah! Not at all!
うん　ないない
Huh?
Oh, I'll go look for swimsuits.
あ　あたしちょっと水着見てきます
Ah, the swimsuits are over there.
あ　水着ならあっちにありましたよ
Really?
本当？
It's fine.
いいんだもん　どうせパジャマなんだから
These are just pajamas.
I'm not going to show them to anyone else.
他人に見せるわけじゃないし
What do you think about these?
これどう？
Saten-san, those are a bit too revealing...
Okay, now's my chance...
よし　今のうち
一瞬合わせてみるだけだから
I'll try them on for just a second...
それっ
There!
What you doing, Biribiri?
何やってんだ　ビリビリ
W-Why are you here!?
な　何であんたがここにいんのよ
I'm not allowed to be here?
いちゃいけないのかよ
Onii-chan!
お兄ちゃん
Oh, you're the onee-chan from Tokiwadai!
あ　常盤台のお姉ちゃんだ
Huh?
Oh, you're the bag girl.
おぉ　鞄の
Onii-chan? She's your sister?
お兄ちゃんって　あんた妹がいたの？
Nope.
違う　違う 俺はこの子が洋服店探してるって言うから
She told me she was looking for a clothing store, so I brought her here.
ここまで案内してきただけだ
Onii-chan took me here!
あのね　お兄ちゃんに連れてきてもらったんだ
私もテレビの人みたいに
I'm going to dress up like the people on TV with stylish clothes!
お洋服でオシャレするんだもん
I see.
そうなんだ　今でも十分オシャレで可愛いわよ
You're already really stylish and cute, though!
Unlike a certain someone who wears short pants.
短パンの誰かさんと違ってな
What!? You wanna fight?
何を　やる気
だったら　五つ夜の決着を今ここで
I think it's about time to settle our little duel!
Huh?
Don't you have anything else on your mind?
あ？　お前の頭の中はそれしかないのかよ
Are you really going to start fighting around all of these people?
だいたい　こんな人の多い場所で始めるつもりですか
Hey, onii-chan, I want to take a look over there.
ねね　お兄ちゃん　あっち見たい
Oh, okay.
お　分かった
じゃね　お姉ちゃん　バイバイ
Bye-bye, onee-chan.
Huh?
あれ　どうかしたんですか
Did something happen?
Nothing.
何でもない
That guy really messes with my head...
どうもアイツが相手だと　調子狂うのよね
Gekota!?
ゲコ太
Or not...
じゃないか
Wait, it doesn't look like him at all.
つーか全然似ってないし
What if they're just copycat crimes? You know, they all look the same, but have different perps.
もしかして　手口は同じだけど　同一犯じゃないとか
No way.
まさか
Well, I was just throwing it out there, anyway.
言って見ただけ
I absolutely cannot find any connections.
あまりにも関連性が見えないから
We've gotta hurry up unless we want another victim on our hands!
急ぎませんと　また次の犠牲者が出るかもしれませんわ
At the very least, we need some sort of clue.
せめて　手がかりを見つけないと
Nine of our colleagues have been injured already.
同僚が九人も負傷してるし
Nine?
九人
Anything wrong?
どうかした？
幾ら何でも　多過ぎません？
Isn't that way too many?
は？まさかターゲットは
It can't be! The target is...
The satellite is picking up graviton acceleration readings!
衛星が重力子の加速を確認
Uiharu, your  cell is ringing.
初春　携帯鳴ってない？
Oh, it is.
あ　本当だ
Hello-
はい　もしもし
Uiharu!
<Graviton>
初春　虚空爆破事件の続報ですの
I have a follow-up on the Graviton Case!
Academy City's surveillance satellite has detected an explosive graviton acceleration!
学園都市の監視衛星が重力子の爆発的加速を観測しましたの
Where is it happening?
か　観測地点は？
We're requesting deployment of the nearby Antiskills now!
<Antiskill>
今は近くの警備員を救護させるよ手配していますの
You get your butt back here pronto!
あなたは速やかにこちらに戻りなさい
I'm asking you for the location!
ですから　観測地点を
"Seventh Mist," a clothing boutique in the Seventh Academic District!
第七学区の洋服店　「セブンスミスト」ですの
「セブンスミスト」
Seventh Mist?
Perfect timing!
ちょうどいいです　私今そこにいます
I'm there right now!
すぐ避難誘導を開始します
I'll tell everyone to evacuate immediately!
Uiharu?
初春　もしもし　もしもし
Hello? Hello!?
What the hell?
何ですって？
初春さん　どうかしたの？
Is anything wrong, Uiharu-san?
Please stay calm and listen to me.
落ち着いて聞いてください
We now know what their next target is.
犯人の次の標的が分かりました
It's this very store.
この店です
W-What!?
な　何ですって？
Misaka-san, I'm sorry to ask you this, but can you help us evacuate the patrons?
御坂さん　すみませんが　避難誘導に協力してください
Understood.
分かった
Saten-san, please evacuate.
佐天さんは避難を
Okay...
うん　初春も気をつけてね
Uiharu, take care of yourself.
The target this time is...
今回のターゲットは
All customers:
お客様にご案内を申し上げます
Due to a malfunction with the electric equipment in our store,
店内で電気系統の故障が発生したため
we will have to cease operations for today. We are very sorry.
誠に勝手ながら　本日の営業を終了させていただきます
Staff members will lead you to the exits.
係委員はお出口までご案内します
We apologize for the inconvenience.
What do they mean by "malfunction?"
故障って何？
来たばっかなのに
We just got here.
Biribiri.
ビリビリ
Did you see that kid?
あの子見なかったか？
What?
は？一緒じゃなかったの？
She wasn't with you?
外にいないんだ
She wasn't outside.
She could still be inside!
もしかして　まだ中に
What were you doing!?
何やってんのよ？
Hey!
っあ　おい
初春
Uiharu!
We've finished evacuating everyone.
全員避難終わりました
今すぐそこを離れなさい
Get the hell out of there!
Huh?
え？
過去の事件の人的被害は
All of the casualties in previous cases have been Judgment members!
<Judgement>
風紀委員だけですの
The criminal's real target is the Judgment member closest to their targeted location!
<Judgement>
犯人の真の狙いは観測地点周辺にいる風紀委員
今回のターゲットはあなたですのよ　初春
He's got his sights set on you, Uiharu!
What!?
Onee-chan!
お姉ちゃん
That's...
あれは
A guy with glasses told me to give this to you.
眼鏡を掛けたお兄ちゃんがお姉ちゃんに渡してって　はい
Here.
逃げてください　あれが爆弾です
Get away!
That's a bomb!
I'll blow the bomb away with my Railgun!
<Railgun>
超電磁砲で爆弾ごと
Shi-
しまっ
What was that!?
何だ
It blew up!
爆発したぞ
It must be one of those terrorist bombings!
例の連続爆破テロじゃない？
It looked like there were people still inside!
まだ中に人がいるみたいだぞ
Someone said they saw a Judgment girl!
<Judgement>
風紀委員の子を見たって
It's dangerous! Stand back!
危険です　下がって　下がって
Stand back!
This is great.
いいぞ　凄い　素晴らしい
Amazing.
It's fabulous.
I'm starting to be able to use stronger powers, bit by bit.
徐々に強い力を使いこなせるようになってきた
もうすぐだ
Just a little more.
I can take out those worthless Judgment peons and those delinquents with just a little more practice...
あと少し数をこなせば
<Judgement>
無能な風紀委員もあの不良どもも
I'll gather them all together and blow them up-
みんなまとめて吹き飛ばっ
What just happened?
一体何が
Hi!
ハイ
I don't need to tell you why I'm here, do I?
要件は言わなくても分かるわよね　爆弾魔さん
Mr. Mad Bomber.
I-I have no idea what you're talking about.
な　何の事だか 僕にはさっぱり
Well,
まぁ　確かに威力は大したもんよね
I have to say, your destructive power is pretty impressive.
Unfortunately for you, however...
でも　残念　死傷者どころか
...you failed to kill anyone. In fact, no one's gotten so much as a scratch.
誰一人カスリ傷一つ負ってないわよ
N-No way...
そ　そんな　バカなっ
僕の最大出力だぞ
That was my maximum output!
Oh, really?
Um... It looked really crazy from outside, too...
いや　外から見ても凄い爆発だったんで
I was sure that the people inside wouldn't be able to survive-
中の人がとても助からないんじゃないかって
Railgun.
<Railgun>
超電磁砲
The ace of Tokiwadai.
今度は常盤台のエース様か
It's always like this.
いつもこうだ
何をやっても
No matter what I do, I just get beaten back down.
力で地面にねじ伏せられる
I'll kill you.
殺してやる
People like you are at fault here!
お前みたいなのが悪いんだよ
Judgment is too!
<Judgement>
風紀委員だって同じだ
力のあるヤツはみんなそうだろうが
Everyone with power is like you!
Power, power...
力　力って
Bite down hard!
歯を食いしばれ
Damn you.
ったく
It's only natural.
殴られて当然ですわ
She hit you because she considers people who use "power" as an excuse to be unforgivable.
あなたみたいに力を言いわけにする人は
一番許せないタイプでしょから
Hey, did you know this?
ご存知かしら
Tokiwadai's Railgun began as a Level One.
<Railgun>
常盤台の超電磁砲は
<Level 1>
元々は単なる低能力者でした
However, she managed to become a Level Five through extraordinary effort.
並々ならぬ努力によって
<Level 5>
超能力者と呼ばれる力を得たんですの
That said, even if she were still a Level One...
<Level 1>
でも　例え低能力者だったとしても
...she would have still stood up against you.
お姉様はあなたの前に立ち塞がったでしょ
Shirai-san!
白井さん
Geez, I was really worried.
もう　心配しましたのよ
ごめんなさい
I'm sorry.
でも　御坂さんのおかげで
But, thanks to Misaka-san...
ほーら　この通り
Look, I'm fine!
The Tokiwadai onee-chan saved us!
常盤台のお姉ちゃんが助けてくれたの
Right?
ね
カッコ良かったね
She was so cool!
Right?
ね
But, really...
それにしても
Only the place where Uiharu and the others were at remained unscathed...
初春たちがいた場所だけ無傷だなんて
How could she pull that off with her Ability?
能力をどう使ったらこういう風になりますの
Onee-sama
お姉様
You did a really great job!
今回は本当にお手柄でしたの
Thank you so much!
ありがとうございます
Kuroko will do anything you desire today!
黒子　今日はお姉様の望む事何でもして差し上げますわ
I'll wash your back or give you a message.
お背中流したり　マッサージしたり　何でもおっしゃって
Ask me for anything!
Hey, that's what you want.
それ　あんたの欲望でしょ　遠慮しとく
I'll pass.
Oh, come on, Onee-sama!
あ　そんな　お姉様
Dear My Friend Every day & night
Always be with you
Dear My Friend every day & night
話しても　まだまだ　足りないまま
夕焼けが　街を染めてゆく
思うように　なかなか　いかない…って
気づいたら　一緒に　泣いていた
恋も　夢も　花も　虹も　風も
ぜんぶ掴もうよ
ダイジョウブ！　元気出して
私がそばにいるから
今日のミス　悔やむより　今　乗り越えて
ダイジョウブ！　迷わないで
まだ見ぬ未来へと向かって
ずっと　歩いてゆこう
Dear My Friend every day & night
Always be with you
Earlier,
<Railgun>
あの時　私の超電磁砲は間に合わなかった
my Railgun didn't make it on time.
The person who actually saved Uiharu-san and the others...
実際に初春さんたちを救ったのは
was him.
コイツだ
Shit, it's an ambush!
っげ　待ち伏せ
Is it okay?
いいの？
は？
Is what?
みんなあの場を救ったのは私だと思ってるみたいだけど
It looks like they all think I saved everyone.
You'll be a hero if you come out and tell the truth.
名乗り出ればヒーローよ
あ？何言ってんだ　お前
Huh? What are you saying?
Eh?
As long as no one got hurt, it's all good.
みんな無事だったんだから　それで何の問題もねぇじゃんか
誰が助けたかなんてどうでもいいだろ？
Who cares who saved who?
Damn you!
って　スカシてんじゃねぇ
Don't try to play it off like that!
Stop acting so cool!
思いっきりカッコつけてんじゃないわよ
しかも私にだけだぁ
You only do this with me, I swear!
That pisses me off!
A Certain Scientific Railgun
To be continued
ムカつく
待
续
Next Episode
Damn, he's always like that!
ったく　アイツはいつもいつも
Level
Upper
幻
想
御
手
L
e
v
l
U
p
e
r
He pisses me off!
あぁ　もう　ムカつく
Hey, now's not the time to be getting all flushed!
赤くなってる場合じゃありませんわ　お姉様
来週は
Next week, you're-
Who did you say was getting all flushed?
誰が赤くになってる
O-Ouch!
ゆ　夕陽が
Um... the sunset!